Dr. Six Lancelot

Software Engineer

7 Kerroc'h
22160 Callac, FRANCE

\$\pi +336 58 16 70 00

\times \text{lsix.job@lancelotsix.com}

\tilde{\mathbb{m}} www.linkedin.com/in/lsix

\tilde{\mathbb{m}} \text{lsix}

I am a research engineer mainly working in developing and maintaining high performances simulation tools. I have been contributing to multiple free and open sources projects over the years, mainly through my activity as a maintainer of the NixOS operating system. I am willing to move forward to a position where I can contribute to FOSS and build fondation tools on which users can rely on.

Work experiences

Since 2013 Research engineer, Quiet-Oceans, Brest, France.

Quiet-Oceans is a leading consulting company specialized in under-water noise study. We offer both $in\ situ$ measurement and analyses of noise with custom-made instruments and software as well as noise map modelings.

Modeling software developed by Quiet-Oceans is used to estimate, understand and evaluate risk mitigation strategies for human activities at sea.

Main responsibilities:

- Develop and maintain the high performance simulation tool "Quonops" (C++), and associated statistical analysis tools (Python and C++) Lead developer,
- Develop embedded software for sound acquisition and processing in close relation with acousticians (C++ / Python) Lead developer,
- System administration of our modeling cluster,
- Creation of "Quonops Online Services", a web platform built around Quonops' capabilities (Python) Team member.

Keywords: C++, HPC, Python, Haskell, Kubernetes

2018 **Teacher (lab work supervisor)**, *IMT-atlantique*, Brest, France.

Supervising labs about distributed programming in the Engineering school. Technologies involved ranged from plain sockets to MPI programming (in C and C++).

2010–2013 **Doctoral candidate**, *IFSTTAR*, Paris, France.

My research focussed on multi-agent system based simulation models during my PhD. I improved an existing road traffic microscopic model while proposing a validation driven incremental development process.

Keywords: Software Engineering methodology, Multi-Agent Systems, Archisim

2010–2013 **Teacher (seminar teacher and lab work supervisor)**, Pierre and Marie Curie University (Sorbonne University), Paris, France.

Teaching C, Java, Assembly (introduction) Scheme and mathematics applied to computer sciences to bachelor students (seminars and practical work sessions).

2010 (6 month) Intern, Gemalto — R&D, Beijing, China.

I worked on a high availability (HA) telecommunications platform. I was in charge of designing and implementing and testing the HA aspects of the application, which includes replication, configuration synchronisation and recovery.

Keywords : Java EE

2009–2010 **Developer**, *Pentila*, Le bourget-du-lac, France.

Development of a digital working environment designed to be used in middle School in Savoie - France.

2009 Intern, Pentila, Le bourget-du-lac, France.

Framework assessment to prepare the development of a digital working environment.

Education

2010–2014 **PhD in Computer Sciences**, Pierre and Marie Curie University (Sorbonne University), Paris, France.

Development of Multi-Agent System based simulation tool to study road traffic. "Towards a heavy vehicules behavioural model using an incremantal verification based approach and hysteresis: The ArchiPL model". Thesis defende on November 5th, 2014

2009–2010 Master degree in Computer Sciences, Savoie Mont Blanc University, Chambéry, France.

2008–2009 **Baschelor of honours in Software development**, *GMIT*, Galway, Irland.

Baschelor degree done in the context of the european ERASMUS program.

2005–2008 **Baschelor in Computer Sciences**, Savoie Mont Blanc University, Chambéry, France.

Professional Skills

Languages French (native), English (fluent)

Programming C++, Python, Haskell, Ada

languages

Tools SCM (git), nix, autotools, cmake, gdb

System GNU/Linux

administration

Other Work with a remote and distributed team (online communication, peer review)

Free Software contributions

Since 2014 Maintainer within the NixOS project (https://nixos.org).

Regular contributions to the NixOS operating system. I am now a maintainer with commit access.

2012–2015 Member of Ada-France.

Ada-France is the French user group of the Ada programming language. It organises meetings, presentations in FOSS conferences...

Various FOSS contributions.

Over the years, I have contributed to FOSS projects (QGis, i3, poezio...), mainly to improve support of various operating systems (including NixOS).

Interests and Activities

Hobbies Woodworking, Free software contributor and supporter

Sport Bouldering

Traveling Cycle touring

Computer I study functional programming languages (mainly Haskell). This proves to sciences be beneficial in my daily work as a C++/Python developer.